Pass!
Hold up!
-Over here!
-I got it!
Got it!
Over here!
Over there!
I’m basketball genius Hanamichi Sakuragi.
Check out my superiority!
"Birth of a basketball genius?!"
I'm sorry, Sakuragi-kun.
I like Oda-kun of the basketball team.
Shock!
Congratulations, Hanamichi!
Shot down by 50 girls in middle school!
An unbreakable record!
You bunch of…
KANAGAWA PREFECTURE
SHOHOKU SENIOR HIGH SCHOOL
YEAR 1, CLASS 7
Hey, Yohei. How's Hanamichi holding up?
Still haven't gotten over it.
He's wallowing in his own self-pity.
I'd thought he'd get over it
in high school.
He's pretty introverted, you know…
even with his red hair.
I like Oda-kun of the basketball team…
Yo, Hanamichi!
Cheer up! What's so great
about the basketball team anyway?
Bad move, Ohkusu.
The word basketball is
strictly off-limits.
HEISEI MANUFACTURER BISCUIT
Hey, should you be snacking
on biscuits during break?
Basket…
You should watch your diet more.
You should play basketball more?
Last night I saw the movie
The Thief of Baghdad, and…
The Thief of Basketball?
What’s so great
about Oda-kun of the basketball team…
Probably some dumb jock…
I friggin' hate the basketball team!
All the world's in spring
while my heart's still in winter…
Excuse me…
Do you like basketball?
What?
Just my type…
You're so tall!
I wonder who'd be taller,
you or Rukawa-kun?
Rukawa? Who's that?
-Dunno.
Wow, amazing muscles!
Your legs, too…
You're pretty athletic, aren't you?
N… not really…
My name's Haruko Akagi.
Do you like basketball?
I love it. After all, I'm an athlete!
He's recovered!
My spring has come!
My spring has finally arrived!
There’s hope yet
for your high school life!
Quit it, you're making me blush!
I will become an athlete!
One-two! One-two! One-two!
Hey! Hanamichi!
This is the third-year wing!
How about these first-year scrubs, huh?
Oh yeah, what a bunch of punks.
Want to rough them up?
-Stop!
Sit-ups!
-Stop it! It’s appalling!
-Don’t do it in the hallway!
The new kids are so full of energy.
Athletic guys are so cool!
Forget it, let's go.
Hey, you. Redhead.
You a first year? What's your name?
I'm Sakuragi the athlete.
Nice to meet you!
Hey, come to the rooftop after class.
Don't wuss out.
Hey!
You knocked the wind out of me.
What's the big idea?
What's your problem!
You want some of this?
I'll knock the wind out of you, too!
Cut it out!
Where do you think you are, huh?
The third-year wing.
Exactly!
Let go. That's enough!
Are you trying to kill him?
Hey! Someone, help!
-Looks like trouble.
-Shouldn't we call a teacher?
Sakuragi-kun!
Haruko-san!
What are you doing here?
Is that third-year student
someone you know?
Just a friend. What about you, Haruko-san?
I'm here to deliver
my big brother's lunch, but…
It makes me nervous coming
to the third-year wing…
Ah, yeah? Me too…
Like hell!
Big brother, huh…
Ah? Where are you going, Sakuragi-kun?
YEAR 3, CLASS 6
I thought I'd stop by
and introduce myself…
D… don't! Sibling stuff is embarrassing…
Let’s just get back to our classroom.
You think so?
-That was amazing.
-Kinda stupid, though.
That was scary…
Did something happen?
Nori-chan!
Letting yourselves get slapped around
by some first-year punk!
Sakuragi, the redhead, huh…
As I recall, he was
from Wakou Middle School. So he came here…
He’ll always be a middle-schooler to me.
This is where
the basketball team practices.
Oh, hey.
Back in middle school,
if I left the ball out like this…
I'd get totally chewed out.
Ah, I was on the basketball team
in middle school.
Incredible…
Now, cut into Haruko Akagi! Layup shot!
You do it, Sakuragi-kun!
To be honest, I'm a bit clumsy.
I won’t be playing any basketball here.
But I love to watch it!
I've watched my big brother play
since I was a kid!
Sakuragi-kun, do you know what a dunk is?
Yeah!
CREAK CREAK CREAK
That's a tank.
That's a spike.
No, a dunk is the best part of basketball!
It's the most exciting play
that gets the crowd going!
When it looks like
the backboard’s about to shatter
as you stuff the ball through it,
that’s called a slam dunk!
In middle school, when big brother
dunked, both sides went wild…
The whole gym would go nuts.
It was amazing!
RUN! JUMP!
Rukawa-kun's dunks were pretty great, too…
Rukawa?
Whoa! Sakuragi-kun,
you can hold the ball? Awesome!
Bah, I'm an athlete.
Nothing to it! Check this out!
Amazing! Say, Sakuragi-kun, can you dunk?
You're so tall, so you must be able
to jump really high!
W… well, I am an athlete…
Come on, try it!
Slam the ball
right through this hoop, Sakuragi-kun!
Jump as high as you can!
Wow, my heart's totally pounding now!
Haruko-san really loves basketball, huh…
She's cute.
Slam dunk, huh… Gotta do it seriously!
Here goes, Haruko-san!
All right, do your best!
All right!
He's running while holding the ball!
Here goes! Slam dunk!
W… wow!
Slam it right through the hoop!
Oh… oh!
Awesome, Sakuragi-kun!
You missed,
but your jumping ability is amazing!
You totally have to join
the basketball team!
Is… that so…
Yes, totally! That is so, so amazing!
He's a savior! A savior, big brother!
Sakuragi-kun will save
the basketball team!
That guy's huge…
as tall as Hanamichi, maybe?
Is he a first-year student like us?
Well, he rubs me the wrong way.
Ow!
Be gentle.
Sakuragi-kun, how's your head injury?
Haruko-san! I'm all better now!
Haruko-chan,
worry more about the backboard.
This guy's head is like a rock.
Sakuragi-kun, I turned in
your application for the basketball team.
My big brother says you won't get in
unless you have guts, but…
You’ll do just fine. Right, Sakuragi-kun?
I have guts. I'll be all right!
All right, good luck!
Haruko-san's so darn cute!
If I could walk with her
to school, I could die happy!
Haruko, you’re so brave.
You talk with such scary guys so easily!
Are you talking about Sakuragi-kun?
Yeah. I heard
from the Wakou Middle School guys…
Especially that red-haired guy.
He was notorious
for being really bad in middle school.
Haruko, you don't get scared
at all, do you?
But Sakuragi-kun's so easy to talk to.
I've never felt so relaxed
when talking to someone.
I think he's a good person.
Ah, it's truly spring…
This is happiness.
Hey, Hanamichi.
You’ve been through this before.
Get your hopes up now
and the shock will just be worse later
when you get shot down.
Haruko-chan's certainly cute.
Has a nice personality, too.
Yep, it's true!
You think a girl like that
doesn't have a guy?
Guys can't leave girls like that alone.
-Yup, yup.
She's gotta have a guy!
What's your problem, guys?
-Rukawa must be her boyfriend.
-That Rukawa guy…
R… Rukawa?
You’re so tall!
I wonder who'd be taller,
you or Rukawa-kun?
Rukawa-kun's dunks were pretty great, too…
-Rukawa…
-Yup, yup.
Die, Rukawa!
It's not like it's been confirmed yet.
Just ask Haruko-chan directly.
Eh? Rukawa-kun? What… what about him?
Well, I was wondering
if he was your boyfriend…
Look at that nervous response…
I guess Rukawa might be her boyfriend…
Totally! There's no mistake about it!
I guess Rukawa-kun
is your boyfriend, then?
No, not at all!
Rukawa-kun doesn't even know me!
W… what?
See that? Who's her boyfriend, you idiots!
C'mon, pay up, I win.
They were betting on it!
Rukawa-kun is, well…
Yes?
He was on the Tomigaoka basketball team.
I went to Yonchu.
We had a lot of practice games.
The Yonchu team would always
single Rukawa-kun out…
But they couldn’t hold him back,
and they kept losing.
He had three guys constantly on him.
One against three?
Basketball teams have five people, so…
to get three on one, you have to use two
to deal with the other four guys.
Let's see… I get it…
YONCHU
So three guys all tried
to stop him. Tried to, but…
Rukawa-kun landed four dunks
past three guards in that game
and totally wiped out Yonchu!
He scored 51 points
just by himself in that game.
The image of Rukawa-kun from that day…
is stuck in my head even now…
Ah, how could I keep talking like this…
Sakuragi-kun, you make things
just sort of slip out…
Don't tell me…
So, your feelings for Rukawa-kun are…
Just one-sided.
Shock!
I haven't told anyone else about this!
You can't tell anybody,
all right, Sakuragi-kun?
Ah? Sakuragi-kun?
In commemoration
of your high school first!
Congratulations, Hanamichi!
It’s the start of a new streak!
Uh-oh, here it comes…
That's not his usual reaction…
Shh, it's that song again.
This is too sad! Hanamichi!
He was really serious this time…
Hanamichi!
That felt refreshing… ah!
YEAR 1, CLASS 7
Is Sakuragi here?
Who are you guys?
No worries, we'll be gone soon.
Sakuragi! You know what we want, right?
Come to the rooftop after class.
Don't wuss out.
What the hell…
You calling me a wuss?
Uh-oh, he's snapped!
Okay, guys, we get the point,
so get out already!
Who do you think
you’re talking to? I’ll crush you!
Small fry should get lost.
I'm talking to you, Hotta-senpai.
What? Who are you calling
small fry, buddy?
Yohei Mito, right?
This year's first years
are an energetic bunch.
You bastards!
Hey, everyone!
Drop it, or you're all suspended!
Hey, Sakuragi!
Fine. Mito, you bring the idiot.
We'll take you both on together.
Better keep your headcount high,
with so many weaklings.
The idiot? You'd better not
be talking about me, huh?
Hey, don't run! Hey!
Who's this?
Hey, punk. No napping here, get lost!
That hurt…
Come on. Turn around and get lost, punk!
Get your rear in gear!
You're a tall one…
You're the one that kicked me?
What the hell are you doing?
Year 1, Class 10. The name's Kaede Rukawa.
No matter how many there are,
I don’t like being woken up.
In Hanamichi Sakuragi's high school life…
a lone ray of hope finally shone through.
But in front of that light stood one man…
You hate me?
Haruka-san, that’s a misunderstanding.
My life in high school is all messed up,
all because of Rukawa.
I hate basketball.
Slam Dunk. "Go to hell, basketball!
Hanamichi vs. Rukawa."
You’ll watch, won’t you?!